<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://visualizeit-consulting.github.io/astd/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://visualizeit-consulting.github.io/astd/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-03-05T20:36:04-05:00</updated><id>https://visualizeit-consulting.github.io/astd/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Always Stuff to Do</title><subtitle>The adventures of a software developer leading a team discovering the power of Domain Driven Design coupled with Event Sourced Microservices.</subtitle><author><name>Andy Whitaker</name><email>astd@visualizeit-consulting.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">Coming up for air</title><link href="https://visualizeit-consulting.github.io/astd/team/coming-up-for-air/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Coming up for air" /><published>2020-03-05T18:30:30-05:00</published><updated>2020-03-05T18:30:30-05:00</updated><id>https://visualizeit-consulting.github.io/astd/team/coming-up-for-air</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://visualizeit-consulting.github.io/astd/team/coming-up-for-air/">&lt;p&gt;I’ve been wanting to start a blog for the last 5 years, but there has always been stuff to do, that at the time, seemed more important. I finally feel like I’m coming up for air after spending the last 5 years transitioning an organization from developing monolithic applications to cloud ready event-driven microservice applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through a series of posts, I will detail how we transformed our development practices, what we did right, and what we could have done better. 
It didn’t happen overnight and it wasn’t easy, but in the end some of the things to talk about include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Challenges moving off of ClearCase and onto Git&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Planning releases using story mapping&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Real benefits of using Domain Driven Design (DDD)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Adopting Test Driven Development&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Increased productivity using CQRS+ES&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Laughing evilly every time the CI/CD system deploys changes with no downtime&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of this may seem strange since in 2020 containers, microservices, and cloud deployments are old news, but this journey started in 2015 and a lot of 
things were discovered along the way. I constantly lament that even though I’ve come this far there is always stuff to do. And it’s time to get started.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Andy Whitaker</name><email>astd@visualizeit-consulting.com</email></author><category term="lessons learned" /><summary type="html">I’ve been wanting to start a blog for the last 5 years, but there has always been stuff to do, that at the time, seemed more important. I finally feel like I’m coming up for air after spending the last 5 years transitioning an organization from developing monolithic applications to cloud ready event-driven microservice applications. Through a series of posts, I will detail how we transformed our development practices, what we did right, and what we could have done better. It didn’t happen overnight and it wasn’t easy, but in the end some of the things to talk about include: Challenges moving off of ClearCase and onto Git Planning releases using story mapping Real benefits of using Domain Driven Design (DDD) Adopting Test Driven Development Increased productivity using CQRS+ES Laughing evilly every time the CI/CD system deploys changes with no downtime A lot of this may seem strange since in 2020 containers, microservices, and cloud deployments are old news, but this journey started in 2015 and a lot of things were discovered along the way. I constantly lament that even though I’ve come this far there is always stuff to do. And it’s time to get started.</summary></entry></feed>